Guide to the Scenic Houston - Scenic Texas Collection 2008-010
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
Scenic Houston - Scenic Texas Collection
1963-2008
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
2008-010
15.0 Linear Feet
University of Houston Libraries
Scenic Houston is a chapter of Scenic Texas, Inc., a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization that focuses on promoting policies and actions that enhance the beauty and appeal of our streetscapes and roadways.
Historical Information
Scenic Houston is a chapter of Scenic Texas, Inc., a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization that focuses on promoting policies and actions that enhance the beauty and appeal of our streetscapes and roadways. Scenic Houston works to reduce existing billboard blight, prevent new billboard construction, foster attractive on-premises signage, incorporate context-sensitive design in the planning of highways and other public projects, and protect the natural beauty and distinctive character of our communities for the benefit of successive generations.
Scenic Houston's roots are deep. In 1966, concerned Houstonians formed Billboards Limited to fight against the mushrooming billboard blight in our city. Billboards Limited fought to establish, for the first time ever, a City of Houston sign ordinance as a means to create standards and regulations for billboards in the city. Despite overtures from Billboards Limited to work together in this process, the billboard industry fought any kind of regulation and would not compromise. In addition, City elected leadership of the era was ineffective in leading stakeholders toward establishing effective standards. By 1980, Houston was home to more than 10,000 billboards and was known in the media as the "Billboard Capitol of the World".
Such a designation was recognized by not only Billboards Limited but a new generation of community leaders as an economic development black eye for Houston. In 1980, Houston city council unanimously passed an ordinance banning new billboard construction in the city. This marked a significant turning point in the campaign for signage standards in the city, and sparked a desire for statewide advocacy to protect the appearance and quality of life of roads and streets statewide. As a result, in 1984, Billboards Limited was re-organized as The Lone Star Roadside Council, a state-wide non-profit organization. A final name change occurred in 1991 with the establishment of Scenic Texas, Inc. as the statewide entity and Scenic Houston as its largest and most active local chapter.
Currently, the chapters of Scenic Texas are run by a mix of staff members and volunteers. Scenic Houston has been able to attract generous donors from Houston. Successful in its attempts to make Houston an uncommonly beautiful and economically dynamic city, Scenic Houston believes that successful economic development can only be achieved if a high priority is placed on quality of life issues. The organization seeks and supports public policies, at all levels of government, which promote and enhance the visual quality of life aspects of Houston's urban landscape.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Anne Culver, Executive Director on July 15, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. / Portions of this collection are restricted.
Scope and Contents
Scenic Houston is a chapter of Scenic Texas, Inc., a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization that focuses on promoting policies and actions that enhance the beauty and appeal of our streetscapes and roadways. Scenic Houston works to reduce existing billboard blight, prevent new billboard construction, foster attractive on-premises signage, incorporate context-sensitive design in the planning of highways and other public projects, and protect the natural beauty and distinctive character of our communities for the benefit of successive generations.
Scenic Houston – Scenic Texas Collection includes 9 boxes and records from Billboards Limited, Scenic Houston, Scenic Texas, Scenic America, Scenic Austin, Scenic Dallas, Scenic Fort Worth, Scenic San Antonio, Greater Houston Partnership, Quality of Life Coalition, Scenic Conservation Advisory Council, Houston-Galveston Area Council, Facts and History, Minutes/ Directors and Committees, Events, Street Improvement Projects, Sign Projects, Billboards, Surveys Polls and Public Opinion, Ordinances Legislation, Policy, Statutes, Social Events, and Press Coverage.
Articles; Brochures; Legal documents; Maps (documents); Photographs
- Billboards Limited, 1966-1990
  - Facts and History
    - City Planning Commission Report, Houston, Texas, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Harris County Home Rule Commission Report, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - History and Mission Statement, 1966-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Transportation - Houston, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Buffalo Bayou Parkway Historical Profile, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Houston Chapter, AMerican Institute of Architects, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors and Committees
    - City Planning in Houston, Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chamber of Commerce Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Construction Industry Council Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Executive Committee Meeting, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Carroll Shaddock (Director) Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Executive Committee Mailing List, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Street Improvement Project
    - South Freeway, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sign Projects
    - Portable Signs, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lexington Signs, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ordinances, Legislation, Policy, Statutes
    - Billboards - Statutes & Ordinances, Volume I, 1958-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - Billboards - Statutes & Ordinances, Volume II, 1958-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - Proposed Ordinance, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Non-Zoning in Houston, Bernard H Siegen, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Development of Ordinance, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Development of Ordinance - Highway Beautification Act (HBA), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Letter Concerning Highway Beautification Act, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Development of Ordinance and Amendment, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Houston Chamber of Commerce - Resolutions, Billboard Regulation (copy 1), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - Houston Chamber of Commerce - Resolutions, Billboard Regulation (copy 2), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Billboards Limited - Highway Sign Notebook (copy 1), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
    - Billboards Limited - Highway Sign Notebook (copy 2), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Development of Ordinance, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Development of Ordinance, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Descriptions of Sign Laws, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Development of Ordinance and Sign Code, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Billboards and Community Leadership Action Alert, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Development of Ordinance, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Development of Ordinance and Amendment, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Billboard Laws, 1998-2004 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Press Coverage
    - The Motorcar and Texas Urban Form, September-October 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Should Billboards Be Subject to Road User Fees, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Legal Problems of Acquisition and Removal, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - The Great Billboard Cross, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Understanding Billboard Industry - Tactics at Local Level, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bombarded by Billboards, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Sign Regulation Article, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Burma Shave and Billboards, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Litigating Regulatory Taking Claims, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - How to Look At Billboards, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Publications
    - Billboard Newsletters, 1968-1992 (Box 2, Folder 23-27)
    - Billboard Newsletter - Sign Control Advocate, April 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Lone Star Roadside Council (LSRC), 1984-1990
  - Facts and History
    - Reservation of Corporate Name "LSRC", 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bylaws, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Overview, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Articles of Incorporation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Board of Directors, Committees, and Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1991 (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
    - Consent of Directors, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Directory of Contacts, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Minutes, 1985-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Financial Statements, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Advisory Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Prospective Board of Directors, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Membership Solicitation, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Brochures, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Texas APA Conference Attendees, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Member List and Addresses, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Street Improvement Projects
    - Corridor 83 Project, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Legislative Issues, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Transportation 2020, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sign Projects
    - Sign Evaluation Schedules, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sign Requirements for the City of Helotes, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Press Coverage
    - LSRC Press Coverage, 1985-1987; 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising
    - Responses from Foundations - funds and grants, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Fundraising Reports, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Funding Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Fundraising Letters, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Responses from Corporations, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Corporate Solicitations, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Foundation Solicitations, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Scenic Houston, 1990-2008
  - Facts and History
    - Arthur Coleman Comey - Houston, Tenttative plan for its development, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Scenic Houston/Fact Sheet, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Brochures, 2010-2012 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Board of Directors and Memberships
    - Minutes - Scenic Houston/Texas, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 28-30)
    - Minutes - Scenic Houston/Texas, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
    - Minutes - Executive Committee Meeting, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Minutes - Scenic Houston Board of Directors, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
    - Minutes - Scenic Houston Board of Directors, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - Minutes - Scenic Houston Board of Directors, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors - Manual, 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Board of Directors, 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Membership Solicitation Letters, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Committees and Reports
    - Scenic Conservation Advisory Council, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mayor's Committee to Review Tree and Shrub Ordinance, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Mayor's Blue/Green Ribbon Committee Correspondence, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mayor's Blue/Green Ribbon Committee Minutes/Recommendations, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Greater Houston Partnership (GHP)/Quality of Life Committee, February 2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Quality of Life Coalition, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The Economics of Urban Freeway Forestation, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Program/Project Descriptions, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Regional Goals, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Quality of Life Action Report, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Counting on Quality of Life - An Environmental Indicator Report, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Houston Mayoral Candidate Forum on Quality of Life Issues, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Scenic Houston Memorandum, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Scenic Houston Expert Committee On Houston History - Members, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Events
    - Annual Meeting, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Gala, 2008-2012 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Street Improvement Projects
    - Downtown/Midtown Transit Street Improvement Project, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Downtown Management District, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Gateway 59/Midtown Scenic District, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Gateway 59 Midtown Scenic District, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - I-10 Katy Freeway, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
    - Broadway Project, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 3rd Ward Legislative District, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - North Houston Association - FM 1960 Beautification Campaign, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Neighborhood Traffic Projects, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Old Spanish Trail Community Partnership, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Port Park, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - US 59/Spur 527, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - West Loop Task Force, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Will Clayton Parkway, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Street Improvement Projects - Scenic Districts
    - Scenic Districts - Fact Sheets, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Scenic Districts - Highway 290 Scenic District, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Scenic Districts - Downtown Scenic District, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scenic Districts - Sign Code Standards, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scenic Districts - Regulatory Affairs and Ordinance Meetings, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Scenic Districts - Scenic Right-Of-Way, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Scenic Districts - Highway 249 Scenic District, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scenic Districts - Project Meeting, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Street Improvement Projects - Texas Avenue
    - Texas Avenue - Brochures, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Texas Avenue - Restaurants, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Texas Avenue - Project Team, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Texas Avenue - Meeting Agendas, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Texas Avenue - Coordinating Committees Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Texas Avenue - Invoices & Development of Project, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
    - Texas Avenue - Fundraising Proposals, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Texas Avenue - Campaign for Texas Avenue, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Texas Avenue - Budget, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Texas Avenue - Funding from Various Organizations, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Texas Avenue - Fundraising Letters, 1998-2014 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Texas Avenue - Financial Report, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Texas Avenue - Fundraising Prospects, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Texas Avenue - Committee Meeting, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Texas Avenue - Historical Markers, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Texas Avenue - Historical Markers, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Texas Avenue - Landscape Proposals, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Texas Avenue - Peter Boyle - Invoices, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Texas Avenue - Margaret Lawler - Invoices, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Texas Avenue - Mary Anne Piacentini - Invoices, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Texas Avenue - Betty Chapman - Invoices, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Texas Avenue - Brochures, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Texas Avenue - Invoices & Development of Project, 2005-2007 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Texas Avenue - Invoices & Development of Project, 1999-2002 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Texas Avenue - Invoices & Development of Project, 1999-2006 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Texas Avenue - Press Coverage, 2008; 1998; 1997 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Texas Avenue - Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Texas Avenue - Proposal for Houston Endowment, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Texas Avenue - Coordinating Committee, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Texas Avenue - Historical Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Sign Projects
    - Zoning Off Premise Signs, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Metro/Downtown Traffic Signals, 1996; 2001 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Stages Sign, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Downtown Skyscraper Signs, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Downtown Wayfindings Signs, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Continental Sign, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Reliant Signs, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Green Committees Project - Resolution of the Board of Directors, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Green Project Evaluation and Research, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Off Premise Sign Inventory, Report on City of Houston, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Image and Awards
    - Downtown Enhancement Ideas, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cable Boxes Houston, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Imagine Houston Focus Group Reports, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Beautification Forum, 1996; 1998; 2008 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Scenic Visionary Awards, 1999-2007 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Gateway Project, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Road Rebirth, Texas Avenue Beginning to Sparkle, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Overhead Utility Lines in Houston photos, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Landscaping and Context - Sensitive Design, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - White Trees Plantings, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Scenic Houston Awards, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Billboards
    - Houston Billboards - Agendas and Memorandums, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
    - Houston Billboards - Agendas and Memorandums, 1992-1995 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Houston Billboards - Madeleine Appel, 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Houston Billboards - (Off-Premise Signs) In Houston, Executive Summary, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Houston Billboard Summary, 1990; 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Harris County Billboard Appraisal, 1992; 1997; 1999 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Major Billboards, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Generic Billboard Information, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Billboards - Westpark, 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence - Billboards/Tree Scope, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Billboard Evaluation for R. Norris, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Video Marquee Ordinance, August 2001 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Eller Billboard Appeal, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Billboard Removal: What Amount of Compensation is Just, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Compensation for Billboard Removal in Eminent Domain Proceedings - Historical Overview, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Surveys, Polls, and Public Opinion
    - Houston-Galveston Area Council (HGAC) Cities Sign Survey, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Publicity, 1990; 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Houston 1993 Candidates Survey (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - City Council, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Accessing Public Opinion Regarding Billboards in the Houston Area, August 27, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Public Opinion Poll, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Public Opinion Poll, 1994; 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Survey Reflects Strong Support for Restrictions on Billboards, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Billboards Survey, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Scenic Views, Spring 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Houston Scenic Conservation Forum (HSCF), October 24, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Survey Responses, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Scenic Houston Points of View, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - City of Houston Survey Results, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ordinances, Legislation, Policy, and Statutes
    - City of Houston Chapter 42 Amendments, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - City of Houston Chapter 46 Amendments - Ordinance, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - City of Houston Chapter 46 Amendments - Sign Code - Sign "Bandits", 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - City of Houston Chapter 46 Amendment Update, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Legal Office Interoffice Correspondence, June 14, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - City of Houston - Ordinance, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Ordinance, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Policy - Goals and Objectives, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Policy Development, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Bus Shelter Advertising History and Policy, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Q & A - Billboard Ordinance, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Making a More Beautiful Texas, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Press Coverage
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1990-1997 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - A Texas McDonalds without the Golden Arches, May 20, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - A Bumpy ride for Highway Cleanup, April 25, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Houston's Batle against Blight, August 31, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Report on Emerald City, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1006-2000. 2002; 2009-2011 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Houston Can Have Prettier Streets, February 11, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Newsletters, 2001; 2009; 2012-2013 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - The Bonham Group- Study, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - City of Houston- Signage Rules, July 6, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Peter Hoyt Brown Collection
    - Peter Hoyt Brown - Rootless: An Architects Journey Through A Chaotic Century, undated (Box 7, Folder 33-34)
    - Peter Hoyt Brown - Rootless: An Architects Journey Through A Chaotic Century, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Peter Hoyt Brown - Rootless: The Search For Belonging In Urban America, undated (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
- Scenic Texas, 1990-2008
  - Board of Directors and Committees
    - Scenic Texas, Correspondence, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, Scenic Texas, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, Scenic Texas, 1999-2007 (Box 8, Folder 7-18)
    - Scenic Texas, Public Officials and US senators from Texas, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Board of Directors and Advisory Board, 192 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Board of Directors Conference Call, October 13, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Scenic Coalition Minutes, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Board of Directors Meeting - Copy 1, March 4, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Board of Directors Meeting - Copy 2, March 4, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - House Committee, December 17, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Board of Directors - A Road to the Future, March 1, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Members And Contacts
    - Scenic Texas Member Solicitation, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Scenic Texas, Contacts, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Street Improvement Projects
    - Protection State Highway 130, 1993-2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - State Highway 90, September 15, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Senate Bill 57/County Option, January 17, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Surveys, Polls, and Public Opinion
    - 994 Scenic Questionnaire Survey Answers, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - State Survey - Candidates To The Texas Legislature, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Texas Cities Sign Survey, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Texas Surveys, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Scenic Survey for Candidates to the Texas Legislative, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Billboard Control Survey, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Planning
    - Plan/Goals, 1993-2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Scenic Byways Appeal, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Public Strategies, April 28, 1999 (Box 9, Case 14)
    - Texas Coastal Zone, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Ordinances, Legislation, Policy, Statutes
    - Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) - Texas Department of Transportation (TX DOT) Agreement, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Scenic Texas Bylaws, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - TX DOT Rule Changes, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Request for Council Action, 1988-2006 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - TX DOT 1% Policy, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Scenic Texas Act of 2001 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - TX DOT, 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Adopt a Highway Grassroots Effort for 2003 Legislative Session (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Billboards and Advertisement Control, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Scenic Legislation - A Road to the Future, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 25)